That's the most fantastic story I've ever heard.
这是我听过的最离奇的故事
I can only repeat, sir, what I have already told you.
先生, 我只能重复一下我已经告诉过你的事情
You will get visitors from that other planet.
你会有来自那个星球的访客
Nonsense.
胡扯
It's imperative that I talk to you, General.
我必须和你谈谈, 将军
Get away, old man. Can't you see...
走开，老头，你看不到...
You, will you pay attention? Will you?!
你，你能留意听下吗？能吗FIXME
Get this man back into the observations room. Sergeant, that was an order!
把这个人带到观察室去。中士，已经给你下过命令了
Take that man back to the obs...
把那个人带到观察...
Back to your places.
回到你的位子
Oh no...
噢，不
Come back Polly, they'll blow your head off!
回来 Polly，他们会轰掉你的脑袋的！
Ah!
啊
Now look, I don't know who you are or what you are
你看，我不知道你们是谁，是什么东西
but we've got two men in space, if we don't act now we won't get them back alive.
但我们有两个人还在太空，如果我们现在不行动他们就不能活着回来了
They will not return.
他们不会回来了
Why not?
为什么不能？
It is unimportant now.
现在不重要了
But... We must get them back! When...
但是...我们必须把他们弄回来！等到...
There is really no point. They could never reach Earth now.
这真的没有意义，他们现在再也到不了地球了
But don't you care?
但你们不在乎吗？
Care? No, why should I care?
在乎？不，我为什么要在乎？
Because they're people and they're going to die!
因为他们是人，而他们要死了！
I do not understand you. There are people dying all over your world yet you do not care about them.
我不明白你的话。你们的世界里到处都是要死的人，你也不在乎他们
Yes, but we could avoid their deaths...
是，但我们可以避免这两个人的死...
You will be wondering what has happened.
你会想知道发生了什么事
Your astronomers will have just discovered a new planet. Is that not so?
你们的天文学家刚刚发现了一颗新行星，不是这样吗？
Yes, that's right.
对，是这样
That is where we come from. It is called Mondas.
那是我们来的地方，它叫做 Mondas
Mondas?
Mondas? But isn't that one of the ancient names of Earth?
Mondas? 但是那不是地球的其中一个古名吗？
Yes. Aeons ago our planets were twins then we drifted away from you...
是的。很久以前咱们的行星是双胞胎, 然后我们就离开了你们...
...on a journey to the edge of space. Now we have returned.
...去往了宇宙的边缘。现在我们回来了
You were right, Doctor.
你说对了，博士
But who or what are you?
但你们是谁？是什么？
We are called Cybermen.
我们叫做赛博人
Cybermen?
赛博人
Yes, Cybermen. We were exactly like you once
是的，赛博人。以前我们跟你们完全一样
but our cybernetic scientists realised that our race was getting weak.
但我们的控制论科学家意识到我们的种族正在变得脆弱
Weak, how?
脆弱，怎么脆弱？
Our life span was getting shorter so our scientists and doctors devised spare parts for our bodies
我们的寿命越来越短, 所以我们的科学家和医生为我们的身体设计了备件...
...until we could be almost completely replaced.
...... 直到我们几乎全身被替换掉
But... that means you're not like us. You're robots!
但是...这就是说你们跟我们不一样，你们是机器人！
Our brains are just like yours except that certain weaknesses have been removed.
我们的大脑和你们的一样, 只是某些弱点已经消除了
Weaknesses? What weaknesses?
弱点？什么弱点？
You call them emotions, do you not?
你们把他们叫做情感，是吗？
But... that's terrible! You... you mean you wouldn't care about someone in pain?
但是...那也太糟了! 你是说你们不会在乎痛苦的人？
There would be no need. We do not feel pain.
没有这个必要，我们感觉不到痛苦
But we do.
但我们会
General!
将军！
Ha, that'll fix ya! Europe will know there's an emergency here now.
哈，可以修理你们了！欧洲会知道这里出了紧急状况
That was really most unfortunate. You should not have done that.
那可真是非常的不幸。你们不应该干这个
Switch off the radio and tell Europe that nothing further has happened and that all is well here.
关掉无线电，告诉欧洲没什么事情发生，这里一切都好
I'll do no such thing.
我不干这样的事
That is an order.
这是命令
Go take a jump!
去跳脚吧！
Trigger pack.
Stay where you are.
待在原地别动
You've killed him!
你们杀了他！
I have not killed him. He will recover.
我没有杀他，他会恢复的
Now, someone must answer your commander in Europe. He is waiting.
现在，某个人必须回复你们欧洲的指挥官，他还在等着
I refuse.
我拒绝
You.
你
Yes?
怎样？
Which are the communication controls?
通讯开关是哪些？
O... over here.
在...在那边
Dyson!
Stand aside
站一边去
What are you going to do?
你打算做什么？
You will see.
If you destroy those we shall be unable to keep contact with the capsule.
如果你毁灭那些，我们就不能同太空舱保持联系了
Your commander is still waiting for your report.
你们的指挥官还在等你们的报告
For God's sake Barclay, do as he asks. Do you want the place destroyed?
上帝啊，Barclay，按他要求的做吧。你想让这个地方毁灭吗？
All right.
好吧
Come in Geneva.
请回话日内瓦
Snowcap. What's going on? We received an emergency from you on the radio link.
雪冠，什么情况？我们收到了你们通过无线电发出的紧急信号
I-i-i-it was a fault. We're, we are looking at it now. I'm sorry about the false alarm.
它它它是个故障。我们, 我们现在正在检查。虚惊一场的事我很抱歉
Where is the static coming from? We can hardly hear you, even on these bands.
刚才的静音是怎么回事，我们几乎听不到你们，fixme
It it it, well, I-I-I, er think it must have been the reactor.
这这，呃，我，我想一定是反应堆的问题
We had the moderator on, er, for a time this afternoon and er, well, well that's probably it.
我们把慢化剂打开了，呃，开了一下午，呃，可能就是它
I see. Contact us if you have any further reports on this new planet.
我明白了。如果你们有那个新行星射进一步报告，联系我们
Yes sir.
好的先生
Well done, Barclay. Now the space capsule will have another chance.
做得好，Barclay。现在太空舱能多一个机会了
Now you must let us try and get in touch with our astronauts.
现在你必须让我们尝试与我们的航天员联系
I told you it is impossible for them to get back now.
我告诉过你, 他们现在不可能回来
The force on them is too strong.
对他们的力量太强了
But you must let us try, please.
但你必须得让我们试试，求你了
It is a foregone conclusion. You are wasting time.
这已成定局。你在浪费时间
However, if you wish to contact them I have no objection.
然而, 如果你想联系他们, 我不反对
He and his colleagues may use their equipment.
他和他的同事可以使用他们的设备
Any attempt at deceit however, kill them at once.
然而, 发现任何欺骗的企图, 立即杀死他们
Remove the soldier. I will carry on detail.
移出这位士兵。我好展开细节
Snowcap to Zeus 4, come in please. Zeus 4, come in please.
雪冠呼叫宙斯4号，请回话，宙斯4号，请回话
We have you, over.
我们能听到，结束
Prepare to check orbital density.
准备检查轨道密度
Ready.
就绪
Right Doctor, while they take him out we'll make a break for it.
对，博士，他们抬他出去的时候，我们就冲出去
Eh?
呃？
Then we can get back to the TARDIS!
那我们就可以回到 TARDIS 了
Well how can we do that, boy?
但我们怎么能做到呢，孩子？
Well, we can make a break for it. Down that corridor, the trapdoor and then bolt it from behind.
是，我们可以冲出去。穿过走廊，活板门，然后从后面锁上
Nonsense, nonsense, they'll burn it down in a flash!
胡说八道, 胡说八道, 他们会在一瞬间把它烧了!
We can do with that for a start!
我们可以拿这个开场！
No, Ben!
别，Ben！
If they see you... Ben, for goodness sake!
如果他们看到见你... Ben，看在上帝的份上！
Stop! Come here.
停下！过来
You do not seem to take us seriously.
看来你没把我们当回事啊
Blimey!
啊呀！
Heavens!
老天！
Take him out and look after him.
带他出去，看好他
It is quite useless to resist us. We are stronger
抵抗我们是完全没有用的。我们更强壮
and more efficient than your Earth people. We must be obeyed.
也比你们地球人更有效率。必须服从我们
Uh! Locked... uh! No
啊，锁上了...啊，不
What happened?
发生了什么？
I'm afraid the spaceship exploded, my dear.
恐怕是太空船爆炸了，亲爱的
You mean they're dead?
你是说他们死了？
Now perhaps you can see that your planet is in great and imminent danger.
现在也许你可以看到, 你的星球正处于巨大的危险之中，而且迫在眉睫
In order to save you we shall require information to be transmitted to Mondas.
为了拯救你们，我们将要求将信息传送到 Mondas
Save us?
拯救我们？
What about those poor men?
那些可怜的人怎么办？
Perhaps you will co-operate. Mondas drew the ship away. It was unavoidable.
也许你们会合作。Mondas 的引力把船拖走了。这是不可避免的。
Why? What is happening?
为什么？发生了什么事情？
I will require your name.
我要你的名字
Tell us!
告诉我们！
The energy of Mondas is nearly exhausted
Mondas 的能量已经基本耗尽
and now we turn to it's twin and will gather energy from Earth.
现在我们向它的孪生兄弟寻求帮助, 将从地球收集能量
Gather energy?!
收集能量？！
Age, name and occupation.
年龄，姓名和职业
But for how long?
要多久？
My name is John Dyson, supervising engineer.
我的名字是 John Dyson，主管工程师
Until it is all gone. Age.
直到它消失。年龄
But that means that the Earth will... will die!
但那就意味着地球将会...将会死亡！
Yes. Everything on Earth will stop. Age please.
是的。地球上的一切都会停止。请报上年龄
But you can't calmly stand there and tell us we're all going to die!
但你们不能就静静地站在那里，然后告诉我们我们都会死!
You are not going to die.
你们不会死
And how are you going to stop this energy drain from Mondas?
那你们打算怎么阻止 Mondas 抽取能量呢？
Name and occupation please. We cannot. It is beyond our powers.
请提供姓名和岗位。我们不能。这超过我们的能力了
How are we going to survive?!
那我们怎么能活下去？
Speak please. By coming with us. Age.
请说。跟我们一起走。年龄
With you?
跟你们？
Yes. We are going to take you all back to Mondas. Your age please.
是的。我们打算带你们所有人回到 Mondas。请报上年龄
- His age is unimportant here!
- That's the most ridiculous thing I've ever heard in my life!
- 他的年龄现在不重要！  - 这是我这辈子听过最扯淡的事情！
You cannot for one moment...
你不能一会儿...
Hey, wait a minute! If I was to turn this on the door...
嘿，等一下！如果我把这个转过来朝向门...
...it might blind him! Yeah.
...可能可以晃瞎他！嘢
Hah! I saw that film 20 years ago.
哈！我20年前看过这个电影
Oy, come in here mate, you're wanted! Oy, come in here!
噢，进来吧伙计，需要你！噢，进这里来吧
Blemmy ehny ah fu! Uh!
Now then, Fred!
开动，Fred！
Ahh!
啊！
Do not resist. Give me that weapon.
不要反抗。把那个武器给我
No, I'm sorry mate, I'm giving the orders here. Now look, get back.
不，抱歉伙计，是我话事了。现在，退后
Look, I'm telling you, get back!
看，我告诉你，退后！
You didn't give me no alternative!
你没有给我任何选择！
There's no scientific certainty that this is a dying planet!
Perhaps we would prefer to take our chances here.
You must come and live with us.
你们必须来，跟我们一起生活
But we cannot live with you, you're... you're different, you've got no feelings.
但我们不能跟你们一起。你们是...不一样的，你们没有感受
Feelings? I do not understand that word.
感受？我不懂那个词
Emotions. Love, pride, hate, fear. Have you no emotions, sir?
情感。爱，恨，骄傲，恐惧。你们没有情感吗，先生？
Come to Mondas and you will have no need of emotions.
到 Mondas 来吧，你们就不需要情感了
You will become like us.
你们会变成我们这样
Like you?
你们这样？
We have freedom from disease, protection against heat and cold, true mastery.
我们有免于疾病的自由，不怕冷和热，正在的fixme
Do you prefer to die in misery?
你们更愿意悲催地死去？
But look, surely I... it's possible for us not to lose Earth's energy?
但是你看，当然我...是否有可能不要让地球失去能量？
It is inevitable.
这不可避免
Then you don't mind if we all die.
那你们就不在乎我们全都死掉？
Why should we mind?
为什么我们要在乎？
Why? Why?!
为什么，为什么？
Because millions and millions of people are going to suffer and die horribly!
因为数万数万万的人会受苦，并且痛苦地死去！
We shall not be affected.
我们不会收到影响
Don't you think of anything except yourselves?!
除了你们自己你们就不考虑其它任何事吗？
We are equipped to survive. We are only interested in survival. /
我们装配的目的是为了存活。我们感兴趣的也只有存活
Anything else is of no importance. Your deaths will not affect us.
其它事情都不重要，你们的死亡对我们没有影响
But I can't make you understand, you're condemning us all to die, have you no heart?
我怎么就跟你们说不明白，你们这是在搞死我们，你们就没有心吗？fixme
No, that is one of the weaknesses that we have removed.
没有，那是弱点之一，我们已经移除掉了
All right, get me Geneva, quick!
好吧，给我接日内瓦，快！
Come on, let's have some action. Get rid of these... things!
快点，我们得有所行动。得干掉这些...家伙！
I don't think you should have done that, General. We may have learned a very great deal.
我觉得你不应该那么干，将军。我们可能了解到了相当多东西
Yeah, we may have lost a very great deal, our lives!
是，但我们可能失去相当多东西，我们的性命！
Missile control? Program all Cobra anti-missiles for launch imminent. Stand in readiness and await instructions.
导弹控制中心吗？
What a ghastly man.
Yeah, I wouldn't want him on the bridge.
We'll soon have this place sealed up like a bottle.
I think you rather underestimate the Cybermen, General.
我觉得你严重低估了赛博人，将军
Oh, that's what you reckon is it, old man? /?
哦，那是你的估计吧，老头？
Well, you're entitled to your opinions so long as you keep them to yourself!
是，你有权给出意见，只要你把它们fixme
General Cutler, sir!
Cutler 将军，长官！
Yes, what is it?
嗯，什么事？
Strong signal on the early warning, unidentified.
出现强烈预警信号，尚未具体识别
Well, identify it, man!
那就赶紧识别，伙计！